<chapter>
  <title>OpenCMISS Concepts</title>
  <sect1>
    <title>Regions</title>
    <para>
      Regions are one of the primary objects in openCMISS. 
      Regions are hierarchical in nature in that a region can have one parent region and a number of daughter sub-regions. 
      Daughter regions are related in space to parent regions by an origin and an orientation of the regions coordinate system.
      Daughter regions may only have the same or fewer dimensions as the parent region.
      There is a global (world) region (number 0) that has the global (world) coordinate system.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Basis Functions</title>
    <para>
      Basis functions are the key item to specify the field approximation/interpolation and the linking of nodes and elements to form a mesh.
      Currently, it has two types: Lagrange-Hermite tensor product and Simplex.
    </para>
    <para>
      Lagrange-Hermite tensor product can be further divided into linear to cubic lagrange, cubic and quadratic hermite. 
      It can be arbitrarily collapsed (two or more nodes in the same location) in any one direction or in any two directions to give a degenerate basis.
    </para>
    <para>
      Simplex basic functions could contain line, triangular and tetrahedral elements. 
      It could be linear, quadratic or cubic.
      Arbitrary Gaussian quadrature can integrate from 1st to 5th order (3rd  order for lines at the moment).
      Can only have the same order in each direction at the moment.
      Specifying a basis function automatically generates all necessary line and face basis functions as sub-bases of the basis function.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Coordinate Systems</title>
    <para>
      Regions are one of the primary objects in openCMISS. 
      Regions are hierarchical in nature in that a region can have one parent region and a number of daughter sub-regions. 
      Daughter regions are related in space to parent regions by an origin and an orientation of the regions coordinate system.
      Daughter regions may only have the same or fewer dimensions as the parent region.
      There is a global (world) region (number 0) that has the global (world) coordinate system.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Nodes</title>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Meshes</title>
    <para>
      Meshes are topological constructs within a region which fields use to define themselves.
      Meshes are made up of a number of mesh components.
      Mesh components are made up from nodes, elements and basis functions.
      A new mesh component is required for each different form of interpolation e.g., one mesh component is bilinear Lagrange and another is biquadratic Lagrange.
      All mesh components in a mesh must “conform”, that is have the same number of elements, Xi directions etc. etc. 
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Decompositions</title>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Fields</title>
    <para>
      Fields are the central object for storing information and framing the problem.
      Fields have a number of field variables i.e., u, ∂u/∂n, ∂u/∂t, ∂2u/∂t2.
      Each field variable has a number of components.
      A field is defined on a decomposed mesh.
      Each field variable component is defined on a decomposed mesh component.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Equations Sets</title>
    <para>
      Aim to have multiple classes
      e.g. Elasticity, Fluid mechanics, Electromagnetics, General field problems, Fitting, Optimisation.
      Different equations within each class
      e.g. Bidomain, Navier-stokes etc.
      Different solution techniques 
      e.g. FEM, BEM, FD, GFEM.
      Associated with a region
      Built using the fields defined on the region.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Equations Sets Fields</title>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Problems</title>
    <para>
      Aim to have multiple classes
      e.g. Elasticity, Fluid mechanics, Electromagnetics, General field problems, Fitting, Optimisation.
      Different equations within each class
      e.g. Bidomain, Navier-stokes etc.
      Coupled problems
      Multiple problems in the same region
      Multiple regions together solving one problem
      Have a number of solutions (each with their solver) inside a problem control loop.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Solutions</title>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Solvers</title>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Control</title>
  </sect1>
</chapter>